SHAMIRAH **NTANZI NNANTEGE**

202 Swanson Road Unit 519, Boxborough, MA 01719 | 7814285993 | sntanzi2015@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced Business Analyst with a one-year background in data management and optimization within corporate environments. Specialized in maintaining data accuracy and efficiency while following agile principles to deliver valuable products regularly. Holds an MBA degree with academic expertise in statistical modeling for data manipulation to support informed decision-making.

Skills

- SQL (queries)
- Excel/VBA
- Business Analysis
- Risk Management
- Project Management
- Tableau
- Data Warehousing
- Extract, Transform, Load
- Data Visualization
- Agile Project Management
- Academy Pod

- Problem Solving
- Statistical Analysis
- SPSS
- Team Leadership
- Professional Skills
- Requirements Engineering
- Stakeholder Analysis
- Macros Development
- Data Warehousing
- Pivot Charts

Experience

Business Analyst 06/2022 to 07/2023 FDM Group

- Created and prioritized user stories for the backlog to guide the development team in structuring the FDM Delegate and Learning Management Systems.
- Utilized Jira to refine user stories and maintain accurate work hour records for project tracking.
- Facilitated cross-functional team discussions to develop wireframes and address roadmap gaps for project alignment.
- Collaborated with the product owner to ensure that user stories met their requirements.
- Contributed to increased development team productivity by streamlining the user story creation and backlog prioritization process.

Tableau Developer (Contractor) Global Atlantic Financial group

08/2022 to 03/2023

- Utilized Control-M to streamline data ingestions, ensuring improved processing time and enhanced data accuracy.
- Played a key role in the data migration project from HDP to CDP, minimizing potential data discrepancies.
- Created comprehensive documentation in Confluence, improving onboarding and training efficiency.
- Leveraged Tableau, MySQL, Hive, and Redshift to monitor data logs, proactively identifying and resolving issues.
- Proficiently identified and debugged failed/unsuccessful jobs using Control-M, reducing system downtime and increasing data processing reliability.

Assistant Program Director Cooperative for Human Services

08/2019 to 05/2022

- Supported the Program Director in overseeing day-to-day operations and coordinating activities for clients' Individual Support Plans.
- Worked closely with the Program Director to maintain house finances in line with head office books.
- Focused on promoting independent living among clients through various activities.
- Advocated for the rights and well-being of clients, ensuring they received appropriate support and care.
- Collaborated with the team to lead and manage program activities effectively.

Restaurant Manager Family Owned

02/2014 to 05/2016

- Oversaw restaurant operations to ensure smooth and efficient performance, while maintaining a focus on profitability and exceptional service.
- Coordinated with various grocery suppliers to manage inventory and streamline the supply chain for the restaurant.
- Managed restaurant finances and budgeting to ensure financial stability and compliance.
- Prioritized and delivered high-quality customer service to enhance the overall dining experience for clients.
- Worked to maintain the restaurant's reputation for providing top-notch products and service to its customers.

Education and Training

Master's in Business Administration: Financial Management

06/2022

Cambridge College

- Quantitative Analysis for Managers
- Information Systems

Post Graduate Diploma in Finance : Advanced Financial Managemen

11/2013

University of The Western Cape

- Financial statement analysis
- Statistics for investors

Bachelor of Commerce Law: Business Statistics

12/2012

University of The Western Cape

• Critical Legal Analysis

Certification and achievement

- Business Analytics Certificate, Harvard Business School 12/2020
- Intensive Cloud Computing Bootcamp- 05/202